Guide to the Pratt family papers, 1758-1903
Pratt family papers, 1758-1903
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Pratt family papers, 1758-1903
223
Pratt Family
3 folders.
Letters, legal documents, financial records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Letters received by Horace L. Edgar Pratt, a Protestant Episcopal rector on Staten Island, New York; also, a Civil War draft exemption certificate issued to John A Kernochan, Sept. 10, 1863; Queens County documents including a four year indenture apprenticing Joseph Lawrence to Effingham Lawrence; a bill of sale selling Joseph, a Negro boy; a receipt for a twelve pound bounty for William Aitken for New York militia service during the Revolutionary War; and a proclamation of Governor George Clinton.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Letters received by Horace L. Edgar Pratt, a Protestant Episcopal rector on Staten Island, New York; also, a Civil War draft exemption certificate issued to John A Kernochan, Sept. 10, 1863; Queens County documents including a four year indenture apprenticing Joseph Lawrence to Effingham Lawrence; a bill of sale selling Joseph, a Negro boy; a receipt for a twelve pound bounty for William Aitken for New York militia service during the Revolutionary War; and a proclamation of Governor George Clinton.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Pratt family.; Aitken, William.; Clinton, George.; Kernochan, John A.; Lawrence, Effingham.; Lawrence, Joseph.; New York (State).Militia; United States.Army--Civil War, 1861-1865--Recruiting, enlistment, etc.
Subjects:
Slavery--New York (State)--Queens County.
Places:
United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Staten Island (New York, N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence
  - December 8, 1853
    To: "My Dear Sir" - Rev. H. E. Pratt
    From: Leonidas Polk
  - September 10, 1863
    To: Certificate of Non-Liability to be Given by the Board of Enrollment for John A. Kernochan to be given by the Board of Enrollment for John A. Kernochan
    Re: Draft exemption
  - August 10, 1869
    To: Rev. H. A. E. Pratt
    From: Manton Marble
  - April 7, 1869
    To: Rev, Horace Pratt, Staten Island
    From: Henry G. Pierrepont
  - August 24, 1871
    To: Rev. Pratt
    From: H. Potter
  - September 18, 1873
    To: J. B. Pratt
    From: Signed by J. G. Eaton, Lieut.
    Re: Permit to enter Boston Navy Yard for day
  - December 10, 1873
    To: "My Dear Bro -"
    From: John F. Nancey
  - January 21, 1877
    To: Dr. Pratt
    From: Richard Heber Newton (b. 1840-d. 1914)
  - November 21, 1879
    To: Rev, Mr. Pratt
    From: George William Curtis
  - November 25, 1879
    To: Invitation to Commemorative Reception to be given for Rt. Rev. Horatio Potter, Bishop of New York (no addressee) (printed)
  - March 31, 1880
    To: Rev. Horace Pratt, 137 E. 45th St.
    From: Thomas Hicks
  - April 23, 1880
    To: Invitation and menu for the 94th Anniversary of the St. George's Society of New York at Delmonico's
  - May 3, 1881
    To: Mr. Pratt
    From: G.(?) A.(?)Doane
  - Jan. (?) 24, 1883
    To: Piece of paper with:.. ,"Richard Hoffman, Jany. (?) 24th 83, New York.
  - Feb. 16, 1883
    To: Invitation from the Trustees of the Metropolitan Museum of Art to attend a lecture by Prof. Charles Eliot Norton (printed) (no addressee)
  - Sept. 24, 1883
    To: Kev. Horace L. Edgar Pratt
    From: Steve Massett
  - October 30, 1884
    To: Mrs. Dallas B. Pratt
    From: M. R. Huntington
  - June 30, 1886
    To: James B. Pratt
    From: Wm. W. Jones, Deputy Collector
    Re: Custom House, New York, pass to Assistant Appraisers Office
  - January 1889
    To: State Department Receipt (?)
  - February 12, 1889
    From: (illegible)
  - February 19, 1889
    From: J. Tuttle Smith
  - March 31, 1889
    To: Leopold Schmidt
    From: H. C. Potter
  - October 29, 1889
    From: W. Y. Joly
  - November 8, 1889
    To: Dallas B. Pratt
    From: W. Allen Butler
  - May 28, 1891
    To: J. Frederic Kernochan
    From: James B. Pratt
  - May 29, 1891
    From: W. H. Drysd(ale?)
  - October 2?, 1891
    To: Lawrence K. Pratt
    From: Richard Croker, Tammany Hall
  - November 5, 1891
    To: "My Dear Sir"
    From: Roswell P. Flower
    Re: Form letter
  - 1892
    To: Announcement of "Piano-Lecture-Concerts" of Jerome Hopkins, New York City, 1st Appearances since his European successes...
  - Sept. 16, 1892
    To: Mr. C. W. Leng
    From: C. Jerome Hopkins
  - February 17, 1893
    To: Mrs. Pratt
    From: V. Jefferson Davis
  - April 21, 1893
    To: Rev. H. L. E. Pratt
    From: Louis Fitzgerald, Treasurer, Corporation of the Church of the Epiphany, Mercantile Trust Co.
  - June 3, 1893
    To: Dallas B. Pratt, Esq.
    From: C. A. Dana, The Sun
  - May 3, 1894
    To: Mr. Good
    From: E. Walpole Warren
  - April 17, 1895
    From: Alan S. Webb, The College of the City of New York, President's Office
  - March 9 (?), 1899
    To: "Dear Sir"
    From: E. R. McKinistry, R.M.S. "Germanic"
  - January 22, 1903
    To: Dallas Bache Pratt
    From: Geo. F. Nelson
  - undated letter
    To: Dear Aunt Kate
    From: N. (?) Taber
  - Oct. 5, no date
    To: "My Dear Mr. Pratt"
    From: J. H. Stoddart (perhaps the actor, James Henry, 1827-1907)
    Re: Declines invitation
  - no date
    To: Slip of paper; "House of Rep's, U. S. Public Document. Free. M. C." (printed). "S. S. Cox, John S. Leng, Esqr., Iron Merchant, No 4 Fletcher St., New York City, N.Y/ (written).
  - no date
    To: Slip of paper: "J. Hyatt Smith M. C."
  - no date
    To: Fragment of paper, "Long" and "S S Col M. C."
  - no date
    To: Fragment of paper, "House of Representatives U. S. Part of Cong. Record. Free. L. K. Pratt, 1017 Lex. Av., NY, R (illegible), M. C.
  - no date
    To: Slip of paper: "Votre tout Dévané: Cte de Lippe-Weisenfeld"
- Correspondents
  Additional information on certain correspondents and their letters or other papers
  - Buttler, William Allen, 1825-1902.
    Lawyer, author. Letter of introduction to Dallas B. Pratt, November 8, 1889
  - Clinton, George, 1739-1812.
    Governor of New York. Proclamation, August 20, 1784, in own handwriting, convening Assembly.
  - Croker, Richard, 1841-1922.
    Typed letter to Lawrence K. Pratt, October 27, 1891, sending Pratt two tickets to a business men's meeting.
  - Curtis, George William, 1824-1892.
    Journalist, lecturer, author. Letter to Rev. Horace Pratt, November 21, 1879, referring to election of 1879. "The result of the election seems to me very valuable as showing that there is independence enough to hold machines in check."
  - Dana, Charles Anderson, 1819-1897.
    Editor, New York Sun. Letter to Dallas B. Pratt, June 3, 1893, introducing Gerrit Smith Glen, who was organizing "The National Continental League" for the political union of the United States and Canada by "honorable and peaceful means."
  - Davis, Varina Howell, 1826-1906.
    Mrs. Jefferson Davis. Letter to Mrs. Dallas Bache Pratt asking that daughter be excused from dinner party because of illness. February 17, 1893.
  - Doane, George Hobart, 1830-?
    Prelate of Catholic Church in later life, having left the Protestant Episcopal Church in 1855. Letter, May 3, 1881, saying he can't attend the wedding of his godson and Amy Pratt.
  - Flower, Roswell Pettibone, 1835-1899.
    Typed letter, November 1891, thanking an unidentified person for congratulations on Flower's election as Governor.
  - Hopkins, Charles Jerome, 1836-?
    Composer, pianist, lecturer. Printed bill, advertising lecture-concert, May 5, 1892. Letter to C.W. Leng, September 16, 1892.
  - Kernochan, John A
    "Certificate of non-liability to be given by the board of enrollment." John A Kernochan of New York City has given "satisfactory evidence that he is not properly subject to do military duty.. ." September 10, 1863. Letter to James B. Pratt from J. Frederick Kernochan concerning estate of J.A.K., May 28, 1891.
  - Marble, Manton Malone, 1835-1917
    A founder of the New York World. Letter, August 10, 1867, replying to Rev. H.L.E. Pratt, saying that the World would be pleased for an "occasional letter" during Pratt's projected southern trip.
  - Nelson, George Francis, 1842-1932.
    Protestant Episcopal clergyman, Secretary to Bishop of New York (1886-1908), Canon of St. John the Divine after 1911. Letter of introduction to Dallas Bache Pratt, January 22, 1903.
  - Newton, Richard Heber, 1840-1914.
    Protestant Episcopal clergyman, author. All Souls Church, New York City. Thank-you note, January 2, 1877, to Rev. Pratt.
  - Pierrepont, Henry I.
    Letter, April 7, 1869, requesting Rev. Horace L. Edgar Pratt to preach one Sunday at Grace Church, Brooklyn.
  - Polk, Leonidas K, 1806-1364.
    Bishop, Protestant Episcopal Church, Louisiana. Founder, University of the South, Sewanee, Tennessee, 1860. Letter, December 8, 1853 to Rev. H.L.E Pratt concerning a Post for Pratt in the south. Discussion of salaries.
  - Potter, Henry Codman, 1834-1908.
    Nephew of Horatio, Bishop of New York after 1887. Letter, March 31, 1839, to warden of Church of Holy Sepulchre.
  - Potter, Horatio,1802-1887.
    Bishop of New York. Letter, August 24, 1871, to Rev. Pratt, about a forthcoming visit of Potter to the Staten Island church. Printed invitation to a reception, November 25, 1879, celebrating 25 years of Potter's Episcopate.
  - Smith, J. Tuttle
    Letter, February 19, 1889, concerning affairs of the Church of the Holy Sepulchre.
  - Warren, Edwin Walpole, 1839-1903.
    Rector, Church of the Holy Trinity, New York. letter to a Mrs. Good, May 3, 1894, thanking her for a gift for "the summer home."
  - Webb, Alexander Stewart, 1835-1911
    President, City College of New York. Note, April 17, 1895 to unknown person.
  - Young, John F, 1320-1835
    Bishop, Florida. Letter to Rev. Pratt, December 10, 1873, about possible post in Florida.